<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GEO 109</title>
    <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on GEO 109</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 12:24:39 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://uky-gis.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Syllabus</title>
      <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/syllabus/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 04 Jun 2021 12:39:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uky-gis.github.io/syllabus/</guid>
      <description>GEO 109 Syllabus Department of Geography
The University of Kentucky, College of Arts and Sciences
August 22–December 14, 2023
Instructor: Boyd Shearer
Locations &amp;amp; Times Lecture: Tuesday/Thursday, 9:30–10:20 am in the Chemistry-Physics Building, Room 139
Office: Patterson Office Tower, Room 805A
Office Hours: 1–2:30 pm Wednesday/Thursday
Recitation Sections All recitation sections meet in our GIS Lab in the Whitehall Classroom Building, Room 311/313. The recitation schedule and open lab hours can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>02 GPS</title>
      <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/02-locate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 12:24:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/02-locate/</guid>
      <description>Presentation Open in new tab Week 04: How we used to do it 05: Modern GNSS Task In this task, you will try to find virtual geocaches using a GPS receiver app on your mobile device&amp;rsquo;s web browser. A virtual geocache is usually a distinct or interesting feature in the landscape, like a scenic spot or sculpture, that you can find using a GPS and hints. If you find this task enjoyable, Geocaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 GIS</title>
      <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/03-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 12:24:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/03-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Presentation Open in new tab Week 06: Introduction to GIS Task Maps are literally everywhere. From outdoor wayfinding to decoration, they are so common that we often don&amp;rsquo;t even notice them. In your first task for credit, you will explore the ubiquity of maps in our built environment and describe one. This is a popular past time amoung map nerds – just do a search on your favorite social media for the hashtag #mapsinthewild.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lexington environs</title>
      <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/maps/dsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 15:51:11 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uky-gis.github.io/maps/dsm/</guid>
      <description> Map notes This digital surface model (DSM) shaded relief map of Lexington, Kentucky was created in the Blender 3D modeling application using lidar data from KyFromAbove. Department of Geography
New Maps Plus
University of Kentucky
Lexington, Kentucky </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Additional Maps</title>
      <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/maps/additional/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 15:09:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uky-gis.github.io/maps/additional/</guid>
      <description>Maps we&#39;ll use in the course Where is your hometown? link Old skool geocache! link Lexington terrain and track explorer link Maps for getting lost Red River Gorge hiking trails link Daniel Boone NF Scenic Index link Cumberland Gap NHP link Bluegrass Trails link Maps to explore UKy Campus in point clouds link Go See Trees in Lexington link Urban tree canopy analysis link Town Branch Trail link Historical Town Branch corridor link Legacy Trail link Sheltowee Trace elevation profile link Hey, walkers and bikers, watch out!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kentucky</title>
      <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/maps/hill/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 May 2021 15:09:08 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uky-gis.github.io/maps/hill/</guid>
      <description> Map notes This shaded relief map of Kentucky was created in the Blender 3D modeling application using data from The National Map, USGS.
Department of Geography
New Maps Plus
University of Kentucky
Lexington, Kentucky </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01 Data</title>
      <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/01-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 08:24:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/01-data/</guid>
      <description>Presentation Open in new tab Week 02: Data 03: Creating your own Task Maps are unique among visual media formats in that they attempt to show the location of things on the planet in relationship to each other. Because maps can be so useful, we often accept them as truthful representations. But, we&amp;rsquo;ll discover that all maps lie in some way, and they have to, otherwise maps become unusable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/00-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 12:00:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/00-intro/</guid>
      <description>Presentation Open in new tab Week 01: Introductions Tasks Welcome to GEO109! This week we will be getting to know each other, the course, and campus. Please complete the following tasks:
Tell us a little about yourself in this private form. Only the instructors will see your responses. Push a pin for your hometown in this interactive map. (Note: the link goes to a different website – one of our online mapping program&amp;rsquo;s collaboration servers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
