<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Modules on Digital Mapping</title>
    <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Modules on Digital Mapping</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 11:58:46 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>02 GPS</title>
      <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/02-locate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 12:24:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/02-locate/</guid>
      <description>Presentation Topics Open in new tab Presentation Topics Introduction Reference mapping GPS mapping Your Love Letter to Campus Projections Summary Module requirements Tasks Lab Tasks Task 2: Maps at the Gwen Curtis Map Collection In this task, you will visit UKy&amp;rsquo;s Gwen Curtis Map Collection and find a map that you think is appealing. You will take a photo of the map, write a few paragraphs using our provided prompts, and post the photograph and response to Canvas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01 Data</title>
      <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/01-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 08:24:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/01-data/</guid>
      <description>Presentation Open in new tab Presentation Topics 01: Introduction What is data? Finding locations on Earth Data models Practice making points, lines, and polygons Sources of data Types of numbers Summary Appendix: data formats we commonly use Slide notes Module requirements Tasks Lab Tasks Reading Read the first chapter (4 pages) in Mark Monmonier&amp;rsquo;s book, How to Lie with Maps.
Task 1: Find four locations Maps are unique among visual media formats in that they attempt to show the location of things on the planet in relationship to each other.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/00-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 12:00:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/00-intro/</guid>
      <description>Presentation Open in new tab Presentation topics Introductions Our tools Teaching map making How this course is taught &amp;amp; syllabus What is a map? Slide notes Tasks Welcome to GEO109! This week we will be getting to know each other, the course, and campus. Please complete the following tasks:
Read the syllabus. Tell us a little about yourself in this private form. Only the instructors will see your responses. Push a pin for your hometown in this interactive map.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
