<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Modules on Digital Mapping</title>
    <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Modules on Digital Mapping</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 11:58:46 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>02 GPS</title>
      <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/02-locate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 12:24:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/02-locate/</guid>
      <description>Presentation Open in new tab Week 04: How we used to do it 05: Modern GNSS Task In this task, you will try to find virtual geocaches using a GPS receiver app on your mobile device&amp;rsquo;s web browser. A virtual geocache is usually a distinct or interesting feature in the landscape, like a scenic spot or sculpture, that you can find using a GPS and hints. If you find this task enjoyable, Geocaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>03 GIS</title>
      <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/03-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 May 2021 12:24:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/03-analysis/</guid>
      <description>Presentation Open in new tab Week 06: Introduction to GIS Task Maps are literally everywhere. From outdoor wayfinding to decoration, they are so common that we often don&amp;rsquo;t even notice them. In your first task for credit, you will explore the ubiquity of maps in our built environment and describe one. This is a popular past time amoung map nerds – just do a search on your favorite social media for the hashtag #mapsinthewild.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>01 Data</title>
      <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/01-data/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 08:24:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/01-data/</guid>
      <description>Presentation Open in new tab Week 02: Data 03: Creating your own Task Maps are unique among visual media formats in that they attempt to show the location of things on the planet in relationship to each other. Because maps can be so useful, we often accept them as truthful representations. But, we&amp;rsquo;ll discover that all maps lie in some way, and they have to, otherwise maps become unusable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Introduction</title>
      <link>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/00-intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Apr 2021 12:00:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://uky-gis.github.io/modules/00-intro/</guid>
      <description>Presentation Open in new tab Week 01: Introductions Tasks Welcome to GEO109! This week we will be getting to know each other, the course, and campus. Please complete the following tasks:
Read the syllabus. Tell us a little about yourself in this private form. Only the instructors will see your responses. Push a pin for your hometown in this interactive map. (Note: the link goes to a different website – one of our online mapping program&amp;rsquo;s collaboration servers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
